<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.soplos.welcomelive</id>
  <pkgname>soplos-welcome-live</pkgname>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0+</project_license>
  <project_group>org.soplos</project_group>

  <name>Soplos Welcome Live</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Bienvenida a Soplos Live</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">Bienvenue sur Soplos Live</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Bem-vindo ao Soplos Live</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">Willkommen bei Soplos Live</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">Benvenuto su Soplos Live</name>
  <name xml:lang="ru">Добро пожаловать в Soplos Live</name>
  <name xml:lang="ro">Bun venit la Soplos Live</name>

  <summary>Welcome application for Soplos Linux Live with CHROOT recovery and BTRFS support</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Aplicación de bienvenida para Soplos Linux Live con recuperación CHROOT y soporte BTRFS</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Application d'accueil pour Soplos Linux Live avec récupération CHROOT et support BTRFS</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Aplicação de boas-vindas para Soplos Linux Live com recuperação CHROOT e suporte BTRFS</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Willkommensanwendung für Soplos Linux Live mit CHROOT-Wiederherstellung und BTRFS-Unterstützung</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Applicazione di benvenuto per Soplos Linux Live con recupero CHROOT e supporto BTRFS</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ru">Приложение приветствия для Soplos Linux Live с восстановлением CHROOT и поддержкой BTRFS</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ro">Aplicație de bun venit pentru Soplos Linux Live cu recuperare CHROOT și suport BTRFS</summary>

  <description>
    <p>Soplos Welcome Live 2.0 provides a comprehensive welcome experience for Soplos Linux Live Environment. Built with the same modular architecture as Soplos Welcome 2.0, it offers universal desktop compatibility and professional system recovery tools.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Soplos Welcome Live 2.0 proporciona una experiencia de bienvenida completa para el entorno Live de Soplos Linux. Construida con la misma arquitectura modular que Soplos Welcome 2.0, ofrece compatibilidad universal con escritorios y herramientas profesionales de recuperación del sistema.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Soplos Welcome Live 2.0 offre une expérience de bienvenue complète pour l'environnement Live de Soplos Linux. Construite avec la même architecture modulaire que Soplos Welcome 2.0, elle offre une compatibilité universelle avec les bureaux et des outils professionnels de récupération système.</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Universal desktop support: XFCE (Tyron), KDE Plasma (Tyson), GNOME (Boro)</li>
      <li>Complete X11 and Wayland compatibility</li>
      <li>Calamares installer integration</li>
      <li>Advanced CHROOT recovery system with intelligent partition detection</li>
      <li>Full BTRFS support including subvolume detection and mounting</li>
      <li>GParted integration for professional disk management</li>
      <li>Complete internationalization with 8 languages</li>
      <li>GNU Gettext professional translation system</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <categories>
    <category>System</category>
    <category>Settings</category>
    <category>Utility</category>
  </categories>

  <requires>
    <id>python3</id>
    <id>python3-gi</id>
    <id>python3-pyqt5</id>
    <id>gtk3</id>
    <id>gparted</id>
    <id>btrfs-progs</id>
  </requires>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>welcome</keyword>
    <keyword>live</keyword>
    <keyword>install</keyword>
    <keyword>chroot</keyword>
    <keyword>recovery</keyword>
    <keyword>btrfs</keyword>
    <keyword>soplos</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="es">bienvenida</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="es">instalar</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="es">recuperación</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="fr">bienvenue</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="fr">installer</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="fr">récupération</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="pt">boas-vindas</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="pt">instalar</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="pt">recuperação</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="de">willkommen</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="de">installation</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="de">wiederherstellung</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="it">benvenuto</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="it">installare</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="it">recupero</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="ru">приветствие</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="ru">установка</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="ru">восстановление</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="ro">bun venit</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="ro">instalare</keyword>
    <keyword xml:lang="ro">recuperare</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.soplos.welcomelive.desktop</launchable>

  <icon type="stock">org.soplos.welcomelive</icon>
  <icon type="remote">
    <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SoplosLinux/soplos-welcome-live/main/assets/icons/org.soplos.welcomelive.png</url>
  </icon>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Welcome Screen with Language Selection and System Installation</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Pantalla de Bienvenida con Selección de Idioma e Instalación del Sistema</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Écran d'accueil avec sélection de la langue et installation du système</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Ecrã de boas-vindas com seleção de idioma e instalação do sistema</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Begrüßungsbildschirm mit Sprachauswahl und Systeminstallation</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Schermata di benvenuto con selezione della lingua e installazione del sistema</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ru">Экран приветствия с выбором языка и установкой системы</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Ecran de bun venit cu selecţie de limbă şi instalare a sistemului</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SoplosLinux/soplos-welcome-live/main/assets/screenshots/screenshot1.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Advanced CHROOT Recovery System</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Sistema Avanzado de Recuperación CHROOT</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Système de récupération CHROOT avancé</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Sistema de recuperação CHROOT avançado</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Fortschrittliches CHROOT-Wiederherstellungssystem</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Sistema di recupero CHROOT avanzato</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ru">Продвинутая система восстановления CHROOT</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Sistem avansat de recuperare CHROOT</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SoplosLinux/soplos-welcome-live/main/assets/screenshots/screenshot2.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>BTRFS Subvolume Selection</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Selección de Subvolúmenes BTRFS</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Sélection de sous-volumes BTRFS</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Seleção de subvolumes BTRFS</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Auswahl von BTRFS-Subvolumes</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Selezione dei sottovolumi BTRFS</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ru">Выбор подтомов BTRFS</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Selectare subvolume BTRFS</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SoplosLinux/soplos-welcome-live/main/assets/screenshots/screenshot3.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Terminal with Active CHROOT Session</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Terminal con Sesión CHROOT Activa</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Terminal avec session CHROOT active</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Terminal com sessão CHROOT ativa</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Terminal mit aktiver CHROOT-Sitzung</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Terminal con sessione CHROOT attiva</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ru">Терминал с активной CHROOT-сессией</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Terminal cu sesiune CHROOT activă</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SoplosLinux/soplos-welcome-live/main/assets/screenshots/screenshot4.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="homepage">https://soplos.org</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/SoplosLinux/soplos-welcome-live/issues</url>
  <url type="donation">https://www.paypal.com/paypalme/isubdes</url>
  <url type="help">https://soplos.org</url>

  <developer id="org.soplos">
    <name>Sergi Perich</name>
    <url type="homepage">https://soplos.org</url>
  </developer>

  <provides>
    <binary>soplos-welcome-live</binary>
  </provides>

  <translation type="gettext">
    <locale>es</locale>
    <locale>en</locale>
    <locale>fr</locale>
    <locale>pt</locale>
    <locale>de</locale>
    <locale>it</locale>
    <locale>ru</locale>
    <locale>ro</locale>
  </translation>

  <releases>
    <release version="2.0.0" date="2025-12-07">
      <description>
        <p>Major rewrite with modern architecture:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Complete rewrite matching Soplos Welcome 2.0 architecture</li>
          <li>Universal desktop support: XFCE, KDE Plasma, GNOME</li>
          <li>Complete X11 and Wayland compatibility</li>
          <li>GNU Gettext internationalization (8 languages at 100%)</li>
          <li>Enhanced CHROOT recovery with improved partition detection</li>
          <li>Full BTRFS subvolume support</li>
        </ul>
          <p>Patch (2025-12-08): Fixed application switch styling so widgets render consistently across desktop themes; added focused CSS overrides and prepared updated screenshots for the welcome flow.</p>
          <p xml:lang="es">Parche (2025-12-08): Corregido el estilo de los interruptores de la aplicación para que los widgets se muestren de forma coherente en todos los temas de escritorio; añadidos overrides CSS focalizados y preparadas capturas actualizadas del flujo de bienvenida.</p>
          <p xml:lang="fr">Correctif (2025-12-08) : Correction du style des commutateurs de l'application afin que les widgets s'affichent de manière cohérente sur tous les thèmes de bureau ; ajouts d'overrides CSS ciblés et captures d'écran mises à jour préparées pour le flux d'accueil.</p>
          <p xml:lang="pt">Patch (2025-12-08): Corrigido o estilo dos interruptores da aplicação para que os widgets sejam renderizados de forma consistente em todos os temas de ambiente de trabalho; adicionados overrides CSS e preparadas capturas atualizadas do fluxo de boas-vindas.</p>
          <p xml:lang="de">Patch (2025-12-08): Fehler im Stil der Anwendungsschalter behoben, sodass Widgets in verschiedenen Desktop-Themen konsistent dargestellt werden; gezielte CSS-Overrides hinzugefügt und aktualisierte Screenshots für den Willkommensablauf vorbereitet.</p>
          <p xml:lang="it">Patch (2025-12-08): Corretto lo stile degli interruttori dell'applicazione in modo che i widget vengano visualizzati in modo coerente tra i temi del desktop; aggiunti override CSS mirati e preparati screenshot aggiornati per il flusso di benvenuto.</p>
          <p xml:lang="ru">Патч (2025-12-08): Исправлен стиль переключателей приложения, теперь виджеты отображаются одинаково во всех темах рабочего стола; добавлены целевые CSS-правки и подготовлены обновленные скриншоты приветственного интерфейса.</p>
          <p xml:lang="ro">Patch (2025-12-08): Corectat stilul comutatoarelor aplicației astfel încât widget-urile să se afișeze în mod consecvent în toate temele desktop; adăugate override-uri CSS focalizate și pregătite capturi de ecran actualizate pentru fluxul de bun venit.</p>

          <p>Patch (2025-12-09): Removed KDE bookmark remapping logic from the language changer; the language switcher now deletes <code>~/.local/share/user-places.xbel</code> before restarting the session so KDE/Dolphin regenerates localized bookmarks. This simplifies behavior in live images and avoids incorrect localized paths.</p>
          <p xml:lang="es">Parche (2025-12-09): Eliminada la lógica de remapeo de marcadores de KDE en el cambiador de idioma; el cambiador ahora borra <code>~/.local/share/user-places.xbel</code> antes de reiniciar la sesión para que KDE/Dolphin regenere marcadores localizados. Esto simplifica el comportamiento en imágenes live y evita rutas localizadas incorrectas.</p>
          <p xml:lang="fr">Correctif (2025-12-09) : Suppression de la logique de remappage des favoris KDE dans le changeur de langue ; le changeur supprime désormais <code>~/.local/share/user-places.xbel</code> avant de redémarrer la session afin que KDE/Dolphin régénère les favoris localisés. Cela simplifie le comportement sur les images live et évite des chemins localisés incorrects.</p>
          <p xml:lang="pt">Patch (2025-12-09): Removida a lógica de remapeamento de marcadores do KDE no trocador de idioma; o trocador agora elimina <code>~/.local/share/user-places.xbel</code> antes de reiniciar a sessão para que o KDE/Dolphin regenere marcadores localizados. Isso simplifica o comportamento em imagens live e evita caminhos localizados incorretos.</p>
          <p xml:lang="de">Patch (2025-12-09): Entfernen der KDE-Lesezeichen-Remapping-Logik im Sprachumschalter; der Umschalter löscht jetzt <code>~/.local/share/user-places.xbel</code> vor dem Neustart der Sitzung, damit KDE/Dolphin lokalisierte Lesezeichen regeneriert. Dies vereinfacht das Verhalten in Live-Images und vermeidet falsche lokalisierte Pfade.</p>
          <p xml:lang="it">Patch (2025-12-09): Rimosso il comportamento di remappatura dei segnalibri di KDE nel selettore di lingua; il selettore ora elimina <code>~/.local/share/user-places.xbel</code> prima di riavviare la sessione in modo che KDE/Dolphin rigeneri i segnalibri localizzati. Questo semplifica il comportamento nelle immagini live ed evita percorsi localizzati errati.</p>
          <p xml:lang="ru">Патч (2025-12-09): Удалена логика переназначения закладок KDE в переключателе языка; переключатель теперь удаляет <code>~/.local/share/user-places.xbel</code> перед перезапуском сессии, чтобы KDE/Dolphin регенерировал локализованные закладки. Это упрощает поведение в live-образах и избегает неверных локализованных путей.</p>
          <p xml:lang="ro">Patch (2025-12-09): Eliminată logica de remapare a semnelor de carte KDE în schimbătorul de limbă; schimbătorul acum șterge <code>~/.local/share/user-places.xbel</code> înainte de repornirea sesiunii astfel încât KDE/Dolphin să regenereze semnele localizate. Aceasta simplifică comportamentul în imaginile live și evită căi localizate incorecte.</p>

          <p>Patch (2025-12-09): GNOME / Wayland display improvements: robust GNOME Wayland resolution handling with GDK-first detection and a defensive D-Bus fallback; selects best refresh rate and applies temporary monitor changes suitable for Live ISOs.</p>
          <p xml:lang="es">Parche (2025-12-09): Mejoras en GNOME / Wayland: manejo robusto de resoluciones en GNOME Wayland con detección prioritaria por GDK y respaldo defensivo vía D-Bus; selecciona la mejor tasa de refresco y aplica cambios temporales de monitor adecuados para ISOs Live.</p>
          <p xml:lang="fr">Correctif (2025-12-09) : Améliorations GNOME / Wayland : gestion robuste des résolutions sur GNOME Wayland avec détection prioritaire GDK et repli défensif via D-Bus ; sélection de la meilleure fréquence de rafraîchissement et application de changements temporaires d'écran adaptés aux Live ISO.</p>
          <p xml:lang="pt">Patch (2025-12-09): Melhorias GNOME / Wayland: tratamento robusto de resoluções no GNOME Wayland com deteção prioritária via GDK e fallback defensivo via D-Bus; seleciona a melhor taxa de atualização e aplica alterações temporárias de monitor adequadas para ISOs Live.</p>
          <p xml:lang="de">Patch (2025-12-09): GNOME / Wayland Verbesserungen: robuster Umgang mit Auflösungen unter GNOME Wayland mit GDK-vorrangiger Erkennung und defensivem D-Bus-Fallback; wählt die beste Bildwiederholrate und wendet temporäre Monitoränderungen an, geeignet für Live-ISOs.</p>
          <p xml:lang="it">Patch (2025-12-09): Miglioramenti GNOME / Wayland: gestione robusta delle risoluzioni su GNOME Wayland con rilevamento prioritario GDK e fallback difensivo via D-Bus; seleziona la migliore frequenza di aggiornamento e applica modifiche temporanee del monitor adatte alle Live ISO.</p>
          <p xml:lang="ru">Патч (2025-12-09): Улучшения GNOME / Wayland: надежная обработка разрешений в GNOME Wayland с приоритетной детекцией через GDK и защитным fallback через D-Bus; выбирает лучшую частоту обновления и применяет временные изменения монитора, подходящие для Live ISO.</p>
          <p xml:lang="ro">Patch (2025-12-09): Îmbunătățiri GNOME / Wayland: gestionare robustă a rezoluțiilor în GNOME Wayland cu detectare prioritară GDK și fallback defensiv via D-Bus; selectează cea mai bună rată de reîmprospătare și aplică modificări temporare ale monitorului, potrivite pentru ISO-uri Live.</p>
          
          <p>Patch (2025-12-10): Restored legacy Chroot functionality with robust unmount script and exact mount sequencing; implemented cross-DE terminal support (XFCE, Plasma, GNOME) with specific priority lists; restored detailed progress UI and window footer.</p>
          <p xml:lang="es">Parche (2025-12-10): Restaurada la funcionalidad Chroot legacy con script de desmontaje robusto y secuencia de montaje exacta; implementado soporte de terminal multi-entorno (XFCE, Plasma, GNOME) con listas de prioridad específicas; restaurada la UI de progreso detallada y el pie de página de la ventana.</p>
          <p xml:lang="fr">Correctif (2025-12-10) : Restauration de la fonctionnalité Chroot héritée avec un script de démontage robuste et une séquence de montage exacte ; prise en charge des terminaux multi-environnements (XFCE, Plasma, GNOME) avec des listes de priorité spécifiques ; restauration de l'interface de progression détaillée et du pied de page de la fenêtre.</p>
          <p xml:lang="pt">Patch (2025-12-10): Restaurada a funcionalidade Chroot herdada com script de desmontagem robusto e sequência de montagem exata; implementado suporte de terminal multi-ambiente (XFCE, Plasma, GNOME) com listas de prioridade específicas; restaurada a UI de progresso detalhada e o rodapé da janela.</p>
          <p xml:lang="de">Patch (2025-12-10): Wiederherstellung der Legacy-Chroot-Funktionalität mit robustem Unmount-Skript und exakter Mount-Sequenz; Implementierung von Cross-DE-Terminal-Unterstützung (XFCE, Plasma, GNOME) mit spezifischen Prioritätslisten; Wiederherstellung der detaillierten Fortschritts-UI und der Fensterfußzeile.</p>
          <p xml:lang="it">Patch (2025-12-10): Ripristinata la funzionalità Chroot legacy con script di smontaggio robusto e sequenza di montaggio esatta; implementato il supporto terminale multi-ambiente (XFCE, Plasma, GNOME) con elenchi di priorità specifici; ripristinata l'interfaccia di avanzamento dettagliata e il piè di pagina della finestra.</p>
          <p xml:lang="ru">Патч (2025-12-10): Восстановлена устаревшая функциональность Chroot с надежным скриптом размонтирования и точной последовательностью монтирования; реализована поддержка терминалов в разных DE (XFCE, Plasma, GNOME) со специальными списками приоритетов; восстановлен детальный интерфейс прогресса и "футер" окна.</p>
          <p xml:lang="ro">Patch (2025-12-10): Restaurată funcționalitatea Chroot moștenită cu script robust de demontare și secvență exactă de montare; implementat suport terminal multi-mediu (XFCE, Plasma, GNOME) cu liste de prioritate specifice; restaurată interfața de progres detaliată și subsolul ferestrei.</p>
          
          <p>Patch (2025-12-10 - Final): Complete quality review of all translations (ES, EN, DE, FR, PT, IT, RO, RU) ensuring 100% coverage, natural phrasing, and UI conciseness.</p>
          <p xml:lang="es">Parche (2025-12-10 - Final): Completada la revisión de calidad de todas las traducciones (ES, EN, DE, FR, PT, IT, RO, RU) asegurando cobertura del 100%, fraseo natural y concisión en la interfaz.</p>
          <p xml:lang="fr">Correctif (2025-12-10 - Final) : Révision complète de la qualité de toutes les traductions (ES, EN, DE, FR, PT, IT, RO, RU) assurant une couverture à 100 %, un phrasé naturel et la concision de l'interface.</p>
          <p xml:lang="pt">Patch (2025-12-10 - Final): Concluída a revisão de qualidade de todas as traduções (ES, EN, DE, FR, PT, IT, RO, RU) garantindo cobertura de 100%, fraseado natural e concisão da interface.</p>
          <p xml:lang="de">Patch (2025-12-10 - Final): Vollständige Qualitätsprüfung aller Übersetzungen (ES, EN, DE, FR, PT, IT, RO, RU), Sicherstellung von 100% Abdeckung, natürlicher Formulierung und UI-Prägnanz.</p>
          <p xml:lang="it">Patch (2025-12-10 - Finale): Completata la revisione della qualità di tutte le traduzioni (ES, EN, DE, FR, PT, IT, RO, RU) garantendo copertura al 100%, fraseggio naturale e concisione dell'interfaccia.</p>
          <p xml:lang="ru">Патч (2025-12-10 - Финал): Завершен полный аудит качества всех переводов (ES, EN, DE, FR, PT, IT, RO, RU), обеспечено 100% покрытие, естественность фраз и лаконичность интерфейса.</p>
          <p xml:lang="ro">Patch (2025-12-10 - Final): Finalizată revizuirea calității tuturor traducerilor (ES, EN, DE, FR, PT, IT, RO, RU) asigurând acoperire 100%, formulare naturală și concizie a interfeței.</p>

      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.2" date="2025-11-29">
      <description>
        <p>Universal disk detection in CHROOT for all hardware and VM types.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.1" date="2025-09-08">
      <description>
        <p>Updated welcome tab links.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.0" date="2025-08-02">
      <description>
        <p>Internationalization refactor and BTRFS fixes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2024-01-27">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release with basic welcome interface and CHROOT functionality.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <languages>
    <lang percentage="100">es</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">en</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">fr</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">pt</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">de</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">it</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">ru</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">ro</lang>
  </languages>

</component>
